



Caio Conti Guidote Ribeiro

Date of birth: 15/11/1998 | Nationality: Brazilian | Gender: Male |

Phone number: (+55) 31999484207 (Mobile) | Email address:

<u>caiocontig@gmail.com</u> | Website: https://caiocontig.github.io/ | LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/caio-conti/

Address: Avenida Novara 59, B02 A303, Belo Horizonte, Brazil (Home)

ABOUT ME

Currently pursuing an **M.Sc. in Computer Science**, field of **Robotics**, at Federal University of Minas Gerais (UFMG), Brazil. Graduated in **Automation and Control Engineering** (Diploma - 5 years) at UFMG with one exchange semester in **Mechatronics** Systems Engineering at Hochschule Rhein-Waal, Kleve, Germany.

WORK EXPERIENCE

22/11/2021 - 01/07/2023 Brazil

UNDERGRADUATE VOLUNTEER RESEARCHER LABORATORY OF COMPUTER VISION & ROBOTICS (VERLAB - UFMG)

- Robots routing problems, navigation, path-planning and genetic algorithms.
- Main work: path design for a ground and an aerial vehicle that cooperate to survey shelves in a warehouse.
- Paper ranked among the top 15: https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/9995748>
- Other works: paths for multi-robots systems with communication restrictions, dubins orienteering problem with dynamic rewards and reinforcement learning for human-robot interaction.

20/08/2021 - 09/02/2022 Brazil

SOFTWARE ENGINEER INTERN LOCALIZA RENT A CAR SA

- Backend Software Developer (30 hours/week).
- Responsible for developing the Human Resources software application.
- C#, SQL and JavaScript.

10/12/2020 - 10/07/2021 Brazil

UNDERGRADUATE FELLOWSHIP RESEARCHER EVOLUTIONARY COMPUTATIONAL LABORATORY - UFMG

- Evolutionary methods for optimizing the design of power distribution lines.
- Software development, designing graphical interfaces and generating reports.
- Funded by the State Electric Power Company CEMIG Distribuição S.A.

01/11/2017 - 30/11/2020 Brazil

ELECTRONIC/SOFTWARE DIVISION MEMBER | MANAGER AVANT - UFMG

- AVANT UFMG is a student-composed team that works with drones automation.
- Electronic assembly, control, computer vision, navigation and path planning for aerial vehicles.
- ROS, Python and C++.
- From 2019 to 2020 served as the Team Manager.
- Participated in the Brazilian Robotics Competition Petrobras Robotic Challenge 2020: responsible for autonomous search and navigation.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

14/08/2023 - CURRENT Belo Horizonte, Brazil

M.SC. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE Federal University of Minas Gerais

- Scholarship holder CAPES/PROEX (government-funded).
- Navigation of mobile manipulators in an environment with humans.
- Robot dynamics and control.
- · Reinforcement learning.

Website https://ppgcc.dcc.ufmg.br/en/ | Field of study Robotics | Final grade 98/100 |

Type of credits 15 hours/1 credit | **Number of credits** 22 (2 years)

01/08/2017 - 07/07/2023 Belo Horizonte, Brazil

AUTOMATION AND CONTROL ENGINEER Federal University of Minas Gerais

Diploma in Automation and Control Engineering:

- Control and Automation.
- · Robotics.
- Natural Computation and Machine Learning.

Website https://ufmg.br/ | Type of credits Hours Attended | Number of credits 3600 (5 Years) |

Thesis Collaborative UGV/UAV Path Planning for Inventory Management in Warehouses. Grade: 100%.

19/09/2022 - 03/02/2023 Kleve, Germany

EXCHANGE STUDENT Hochschule Rhein-Waal

Evolutionary Algorithms, Bioinspiration, Scientific Methods, Leadership, Cross-Cultural Management and Creativity.

Website https://www.hochschule-rhein-waal.de/ | Field of study Mechatronic Systems Engineering |

Type of credits ECTS | Number of credits 25

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): **PORTUGUESE**

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

ROS(robot operating system) | programming: Python, MATLAB and SQL | C / C# / C++